Hello everyone, my name is Amitabh Life. Today
we are talking about car insurance. It is a very
important factor for our vehicle.
However, a survey has shown
that 90% of people do
not pay much attention while renewing their car insurance,
due to which they buy the wrong insurance.
Why do they not pay attention?
You must have also noticed that whenever the
time for insurance renewal comes, you will either get a
message or a call. After that,
you say, "Yes, okay,
we will do it a day or two before the time for renewal." Then,
because the renewal has to be done today or tomorrow,
we are neither able to see anything online nor
offline. Whatever we do, we do it
quickly and leave. Then, if
we ever need to make a claim,
we realize that we have bought the wrong one.
If there is no need for a claim,
we keep buying the wrong one and keep paying
more money. So, today we will
talk about how to
get the right insurance for your vehicle and how
you can get good insurance
online here.  I have already
told you about offline that you can buy it from anywhere
but there are a lot of things online, let's
talk a little about that too.
First of all, at the time of insurance, you have to
check your ID and the
value ID. Actually,
what should be the insured declared value of your vehicle? As your vehicle gets
older, the
value of your vehicle
starts decreasing. Many times I have seen
what some people do in order to show off a little more. If the vehicle is five years
old, they also make an ID for it. That means
if they had bought a showroom for 10 lakhs, then they will
also make an ID for it. After five years,
its premium will be ₹9 lakhs. If the insurance premium is
₹10,000, then the ID will also increase. They pay ₹
20,000 as insurance
premium and think that now if our
car gets stolen, or if
anything happens to our car, or if it becomes a total loss, then
we will get the full 9 lakhs. There is nothing like that.
The ID is also declared
as your vehicle gets old.
She starts getting depressed, a 5 year
old vehicle has lost about 40 to 50% of its value, which
means if you hold on to 40% of the value of Rs 10 lakh, then
its value is only Rs 6 lakh.
Of course, you have also taken an ID of Rs 9 lakh and
of course, you have paid its premium for Rs 9 lakh.
If your car goes into total loss, then
you will get only Rs 6 lakh, which
means it is according to government norms,
no company makes it on its own, you will get only that much.
And if you have reduced the ID as well, okay,
I take an ID, you can also take Rs 6 lakh, to
reduce the premium you have reduced it to Rs 4 lakh, if
your car goes into total loss, then
you will get only Rs 4, then you will not
get Rs 6 because you had paid the minimum premium
on this thing, a lot of people make that mistake,
you should do that. When the
time for your insurance comes, you should
calculate a little, 10 days to 15 days in advance, you have to
see on different platforms, who is
paying less, who is paying more, who will pay less, I will
tell them about them online.
And you can also go to the showroom to find out offline. I have already
made a little detail about which one to buy online and which one to buy offline. I will tell you a little here also.
If you come from a tier 3 city
or a small town, then it will be helpful for you to
go and buy insurance from the showroom
because right now
what happens in these cities is that if you buy it online, then
you don't get cashless insurance in the particular showroom or the particular service station.
If you get insurance from the showroom, then they
give you cashless insurance. If you
don't get it from the showroom, then they don't give you cashless insurance.
I have seen it in many cases
and they won't give you cashless insurance. You will have to pay from your pocket.
You will deposit it with the company and the
money will come from there. The process is also done.
In that case, you can do it
directly through the showroom. And if you
are from a big city, tier 2 or tier 3, then
you can also buy it online. Online, I will
tell you, we are talking about Eka insurance
because I have seen it
in the policy market. I am preferring Eko to you,
why am I recommending it
because they have not made their own separate policy.  I have
developed an application or a website from them, I will put the
link in the description,
you can go from there also. So
what they do is they have not involved any third party in
between so that you can get
our insurance through them, they have
developed everything on their own, so what happens is that
they do not have to pay commission to anyone else,
there also the money gets reduced, then
they have complete control, if you have to
settle a claim or get a loan, then you directly
contact ECO, it is
not like if you have taken insurance from Policy Bazaar, then
you will contact Policy Bazaar, they will
say that sometimes there is a
conflict, so you
can take it directly from ECO,
I have visited the website, it is very well made, it is quite
simple and I have seen that their premiums are
quite low in most of the cases,
if compared to others,
however, now their presence is
only in big cities and they do very well there,
I have met many people,
some of them are my friends too, so everyone told me
that ECO insurance is very good if
you do everything
properly.  You take it this way, you
can click etc. yourself, if there is a
small game then your claim
settlement happens, I liked it very much,
you can also see the link, I have
left it in the description, you can also see that,
then I have also told about online and offline,
who can take it, one more big thing, the
mistake we make while taking insurance,
this is the last point, there are many other
points in this, what mistake we make is that
while looking at our premium or
when we have taken the policy completely,
what do we do quickly, we keep clicking on it,
ok, fine and in that case, our
MCB, no claim bonus, creates a big
mess, it is written in it that
what was your MCB of the last time, in
order to get more discount, we
pay more MCB, see
how much profit we get, from that we benefit only by 1000 or 2000 or
3000 rupees, it is
not more, but if you make the MCB wrong
then your entire claim gets
rejected, so whenever you get NC,
you should be very careful  Do it and
if you have taken any insurance last year
then your NCB becomes zero,
definitely click on that too, whether you have taken
any claim or not, have got the
windscreen changed etc., if
you have taken any claim then you will make it zero, then if you have
not taken any claim then
you will see the chart there,
according to that you enter your NCB and if
you do not know how much NCV you have then you
can also use the option of I don't know there
and then you will take it yourself, our
mistake in that gets reduced, rest if you
want to ask anything related to insurance then you
can ask on Instagram, you
can put it in the comment box, there I
will try to answer you and if you
want to add something then you
can tell in the comment box, rest you will subscribe to the channel,
tell me how you liked the video, definitely like the video,
see you in the next video, thank you